Guide to the Walter Francis White and Poppy Cannon Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
White, Walter, books by
----See: Alfred A. Knopf (WW)
White, Walter, columns and articles
----See: Chicago Defender (WW)
----Afro-American (WW)
---- Graphic Syndicate (WW)
----Johnson Publishers
---- Look Magazine (WW)
----Pittsburgh Courier (WW)
---- Readers Digest (WW)
----Reid, Helen Rogers (WW)
White, Walter, health of
----See: Master, Arthur M. (WW)
----Tobias, Channing - Wright, Barbara P. (WW)
White, Walter, the governorship of the Virgin Islands
----See: Chapman, Oscar (WW)
White, Walter, marriage to Poppy Cannon
----See: Dejoie, C. C. (WW)
----Phillipe, Charles Claudius (WW)
----White, Poppy Cannon (1949) (WW)
White, Walter, marriage to Poppy Cannon
----See: White, Walter (1949) (PCW)
White, Walter, speaking engagements
----See: W. Colston Leigh Inc. (WW)
White, Walter, war correspondent activity
----See: Bohlen, Charles (WW)
----Navy (WW)
---- New York Post (WW)
"Why I Remain A Negro," by Walter White, publicity for
----See: Cousins, Norman (PCW)
----White, Walter (1947) (PCW)
"Why I Remain A Negro," by Walter White, reader reaction to
----See: Reader's Digest (WW)
----note: other responses are filed in the General correspondence
Writings, articles by Walter White, reader reaction to
"Has Science Conquered the Color Line?"
----See: Look Magazine (WW)
----Reader's Letters (WW)
"Why I Remain A Negro"
----See: Reader's Digest (WW)
----note: other responses are filed in the General correspondence
Wright, Louis Tompkins
----"I love you, God" by Poppy Cannon - three pages
----See: Wright, Louis Tompkins (PCW)
Y.M.C.A., the Negro in
----See: McCray, John Henry (WW)
African American authors -- 20th Century -- Archives; African American civil rights workers; African Americans -- Civil rights -- History -- 20th Century; Civil Rights movements -- United States -- History -- 20th Century; Civil rights workers -- United States; Novelists, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; War correspondents; World War, 1939-1945 -- Journalists; Haiti -- History -- 20th Century; United States -- Race relations; Photographs; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971; Bethune, Mary McLeod, 1875-1955; Black, Algernon D. (Algernon David), 1900-1993; Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1904-1971; Byfield, Robert S. (Robert Sigmund), 1896-1955; Cannon, Poppy, 1907-; Cousins, Norman, 1912-1990; Denny, George V., Jr. (George Vernon), 1899-1959; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969; Estimé, Dumarsais, 1900-1953; Ford, Henry, II, 1917-1987; Halle, Louis Joseph, 1910-1998; Hammerstein, Oscar, II, 1895-1960; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986; Hastie, William, 1904-1976; Holmes, John Haynes, 1879-1964; Johnson, James Weldon, 1871-1938; Johnson, Mordecai W. (Mordecai Wyatt), 1890-1976; Lampkin, Daisy E. (Daisy Elizabeth), 1882-1965; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963; Looby, Z. Alexander (Zephaniah Alexander), 1899-1972; Magloire, Paul Eugène, 1907-2001; Mitchell, Clarence M. (Clarence Maurice), 1911-1984; Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1889-1964; Pandit, Vijaya Lakshmi, 1900-1990; Reid, Helen Rogers, 1882-1970; Reuther, Victor G. (Victor George), 1912-2004; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970; Robinson, Bill, 1878-1949; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Sampson, Edith S. (Edith Spurlock), 1901?-1979; Schary, Dore, 1905-1980; Spingarn, Arthur B. (Arthur Barnett), 1878-1971; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972; Waring, Julius Waties, 1880-1968; White, Walter, 1893-1955; Wilkins, Roy, 1901-1981; Wright, Louis T. (Louis Tompkins), 1891-1952; Zanuck, Darryl Francis, 1902-1979; Doubleday, Doran & Company; Ford Hall Forum; India League of America; Johnson Publishing Company; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; Viking Press; W. Colston Leigh (Firm); Pan African Congress
- Correspondence, 1917-1955; Series I; 4.9 linear feet (14 boxes)
  Arrangement
  The series is organized into two subseries: Walter White Correspondence and Poppy Cannon Correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains correspondence reflecting the careers and personal lives of Walter White and Poppy Cannon. Many folders in the correspondence series also contain memoranda, clippings, press releases, and other material.
  For a more detailed analysis of the subject content of the correspondence see the Select Subject Guide to the Correspondence (Appendix B).
  - Walter White Correspondence
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Correspondence to and from Walter White is also located in the Poppy Cannon Correspondence subseries.
    The Walter Francis White correspondence in this collection includes his general personal correspondence, family correspondence, and letters addressed jointly to Walter Francis White and Poppy Cannon (between the years 1917 and 1955). The correspondence consists essentially of personal letters, but many letters deal directly or indirectly with matters relating to the work of the N.A.A.C.P. The individuals with whom White corresponded in each period of his life, and the subjects with which the letters are concerned, reflect the changing circumstances of his life. Though not arranged this way, the material may be said to fall generally into the following groupings:
    1. 1917-1948
    The letters in the collection that fall within these dates comprise only a small fraction of what must have been White's total correspondence in this period. There are some originals, but many of the letters are typewritten copies. Much of the correspondence for this period relates to the N.A.A.C.P., and touches on but does not cover in depth, White's first appointment to the staff of the Association, communist infiltration of the Association, the Scottsboro case, and lynchings. The correspondence between Poppy Cannon and Walter White in this period deals with their collaboration on a play, blacks in motion pictures, colonization, White's and Poppy Cannon's personal plans, and his relation with the N.A.A.C.P.
    2. 1949-1950
    The correspondence falling within these dates is the heaviest concentration of letters in the series. This segment of correspondence corresponds approximately with White's leave of absence from the N.A.A.C.P. White's activities in this period included his divorce and remarriage, his newspaper column and articles, his lecture trips, the 'Round the World Town Hall Meeting', and his reaction to the attempt to oust him from the secretaryship of the N.A.A.C.P.
    3. 1950-1955
    The correspondence falling within these dates is concerned with White's activities and interests outside of the N.A.A.C.P. These included his interests in the Republic of Haiti as well as the general Caribbean area and his interests in and activities on behalf of India, particularly his scheme for industrial development of the sub-continent.
    - "Aa-Amer. - Fa" General (Box 1, Folder 1)
      To: 12 / From: 7
    - Acheson, Dean, 1949 January 31-1951 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      To: 4 / From: 7
    - Afro-American correspondence with Carl Murphy, with clippings, 1950 January 23-1951 January 12, 1955 January18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      To: 1 / From: 4
    - American Civil Liberties Union correspondence with Roger Baldwin and others, 1936 May 17, 1949 September 14-December 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      To: 5 / From: 2
    - American Council on African Education, 1949 October 20, December 9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      To: 2 / From: 0
    - American Council on Race Relations, 1949 August 24-1950 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      To: 6 / From: 1
    - "Amer. Fo. - Az" General (Box 1, Folder 7)
      To: 16 / From: 9
    - American Information on Race and Caste, 1954 March 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Including: minutes, by-laws, and certificate of incorporation
      To: 1 / From: 0
    - American Jewish Congress correspondence with David Petegorsky and Irving Miller, 1949 November 23-1950 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      To: 10 / From: 6
    - American Unitarian Association, 1949 December 5-1950 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Amherst College, 1949 September 19-1950 March 27, 1955 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      To: 6 / From: 5
    - Anderson, Marian with Hurok, Sol, 1949 December 12, 1955 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      To: 1 / From: 1
    - Angell, Norman, Sir
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Pan-African Congress, Box 5, folder 155
    - Askland, Alf, 1950, 1954, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      To: 3 / From: 1
    - "Ba - Bh" General (Box 1, Folder 14)
      To: 20 / From: 17
    - Baker, Josephine (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Discrimination against by Stork Club
    - Baldwin, Roger N. (Roger Nash)
      See: American Civil Liberties Union, Box 1, folder 4
    - Benton, William, 1950 March 28-May 10 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      To: 2 / From: 1
    - Bethune, Mary McLeod, 1949 September 29-1950 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      To: 4 / From: 6
    - "Bi - B" General (Box 1, Folder 18)
      To: 19 / From: 14
    - Black, Algernon D. (Algernon David), 1948 January 8-1950 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      To: 3 / From: 4
    - Bohlen, Charles E. (Charles Eustis), 1944 November 27, November 30 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bonnet, Henri, 1949 October 5 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      To: 0 / From: 1
    - "Bp - Bz" General (Box 1, Folder 22)
      To: 19 / From: 11
    - Branch, Bobbie, 1949 January 23, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
      To: 3 / From: 0
    - Brannan, Charles F. (Charles Franklin), 1950 February 9, February 17 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1950 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1949 June 7-1953 February 28, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Byfield, Robert S. (Robert Sigmund), 1949 October 20-November 28 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      To: 4 / From: 3
    - Bynner, Witter, 1925 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - "Ca - Cl" General (Box 1, Folder 29)
      To: 24 / From: 14
    - Cannon, Cynthia, 1947 August 18-1948 February 24, n.y. 1954 April (Box 1, Folder 30)
      To: 4 / From: 2
    - Carter, Elmer Anderson, 1930 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Cassagnol, Edouard, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Cayton, Horace R. (Horace Roscoe), 1949 October 3-December 12, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Chapman, Oscar, 1949 December 5-1950 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      To: 4 / From: 4
    - Charles, Joseph D., 1947 September 20, 1949-1950, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 35)
      To: 5 / From: 7
    - Chauvet, Pierre, 1954 March 26-1955 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Chesnutt, Charles Waddell, 1930 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Chicago Defender correspondence with: Martin, Louis E., Sengstacke, John, and others, 1949 August 19-1950 August 15 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      To: 18 / From: 10
    - Christmas Card List
      See: Poppy Cannon Correspondence, Christmas, Box 8, folder 19
    - Christopher, Nathan K., 1950 April 1, April 6 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "C. - Cz" General (Box 1, Folder 40)
      To: 21 / From: 14
    - Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art, 1949 May 16-1950 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      To: 7 / From: 3
    - Cullen, Countee, 1929 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Current, Gloster B. (Gloster Bryant), 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      To: 6 / From: 2
    - Curtis, Elizabeth P., 1949 November 9-1950 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      To: 10 / From: 4
    - "Da - Dh" General (Box 2, Folder 45)
      To: 21 / From: 11
    - Darrow, Clarence, 1930 December 21, 1931 December 31 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Davis, Elmer Holmes, 1944 November 23 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Davis, John A., 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - deCastro, Morris F., 1950 March 1-1952 August 22 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      To: 5 / From: 6
    - Deininger, Whitaker T. (Whitaker Thompson), 1952 August 16 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Delany, Hubert T., 1950 February 15-March 3 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Denny, George Vernon
      See: Town Hall of The Air, Box 6, folder 201
    - "Di - Dz" General (Box 2, Folder 52)
      To: 19 / From: 13
    - Dos Passos, John, 1949 July 29-August 1 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Doubleday, Doran & Company, 1930-1946 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      To: 0 / From: 4
    - Dulles, John Foster, 1953 August 26 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - "Ea - Ez" General (Box 2, Folder 56)
      To: 13 / From: 4
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1949 October 3, 1954 December 20 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      To: 0 / From: 2
    - Ellington, Edward Kennedy ("Duke"), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers), 1942 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - "Fa - Fn" General (Box 2, Folder 60)
      To: 13 / From: 5
    - Estimé, Dumarsais, 1949 June 28-1950 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      To: 1 / From: 6
    - Fernós Isern, Antonio, 1950 February 7, February 8 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - "F. - Fz" General (Box 2, Folder 63)
      To: 18 / From: 4
    - Fouche, Luc E., 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      To: 4 / From: 0
    - Foot, Sir Hugh, 1952 August 16, 1952 August 24, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Ford, Henry II, 1949 December 5-1950 April 7 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      To: 6 / From: 9
    - Ford Hall Forum, 1949 May 21-1950 March 22 (Box 2, Folder 67)
      To: 8 / From: 6
    - Frank, Jerome, 1952 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1950 January 27-March 28 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      To: 1 / From: 2
    - Freedom House, 1949 September 13-1950 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      To: 16 / From: 4
    - "Ga - Gz" General (Box 2, Folder 71)
      To: 19 / From: 10
    - Glenn, Alice White, [circa 1949] (Box 2, Folder 72)
      (Folder missing since 1978)
    - Glenn, Alice White, [circa 1949] (Box 2, Folder 72a)
      transcriptions of original letters
    - Graphic Syndicate correspondence with Harold L. Oram, 1946 October 18-1950 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 73)
      To: 22 / From: 24
    - "Ha - Hn" General (Box 2, Folder 74)
      To: 19 / From: 9
    - Halle, Louis Joseph, 1949 October 20-December 10 (Box 2, Folder 75)
      To: 2 / From: 6
    - Hammerstein, Oscar and Dorothy, 1949-1954 (Box 2, Folder 76)
      To: 2 / From: 4
    - Handy, W. C. (William Christopher), Handy Bros. Music Co., Handy Foundation (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Hare, Raymond A., 1950 March 13-21 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      To: 2 / From: 2
    - Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1953 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Hastie, William H., 1943-1950 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      To: 3 / From: 7
    - Hayes, Helen, 1950 October 31 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Hayes, Roland, 1925 September 4 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Hill, Herbert, 1952 August 21, 1954 December 10 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Hill, Leslie Pinckney, 1948 October 11-26 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Hobson, John Atkinson
    - "H. - Hz" General (Box 3, Folder 85)
      To: 21 / From: 4
    - Holmes, John Haynes, 1944-1950 (Box 3, Folder 86)
      To: 5 / From: 3
    - Holmes, John Haynes, 1949 November 28-1950 April 21 (Box 3, Folder 87)
      To: 9 / From: 6
    - Horne, Lena, 1949, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Hughes, Langston, 1950 January 19 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1950 March 20, 27 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Hurok, Sol, 1949 May 4 (Box 3, Folder 91)
      See: Anderson, Marian, Box 1, folder 12
    - Hurston, Zora Neale, 1942 November 24 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - "Ia - Iz" General (Box 3, Folder 93)
      To: 6 / From: 7
    - Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1948 August 11-1949 September 26 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - India, 1949 September 28-1950 March 13, 1953 September (Box 3, Folder 95)
      Correspondence with members of Embassy of India and Consulate General of India including "Proposal for Advertising and Publicizing The Republic of India ..." by Peter Hilton Inc.
      To: 6 / From: 3
    - India League of America correspondence with J. J. Singh, 1944 November 28, 1949 September 24-1950 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 96)
      Including two articles by Singh: Nehru's visit to U.S.A.
      To: 38 / From: 8
    - Invitations, miscellaneous, 1949 August l-December 4, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 97)
      To: 30 / From: 2
    - Invitations, miscellaneous, 1950 January 7-March 18, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 98)
      To: 14 / From: 2
    - Issa, Abdullahi, 1949 October (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - "Ja - Jz" General (Box 3, Folder 100)
      To: 21 / From: 7
    - Jackson, Allen F., 1950 May 10 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Jackson, Lillie May, [circa 1950 December] (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Jackson, Mabel Dodge, 1949 September 8-1951 August 28 (Box 3, Folder 103)
      To: 5 / From: 1
    - Johnson, Charles Spurgeon, 1949 September 30, 1949 October 11 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Johnson, James Weldon, 1917-1931 (Box 3, Folder 105)
      To: 18 / From: 1
    - Johnson, John H.
      See: Johnson Publishers, Box 3, folder 107
    - Johnson, Mordecai W. (Mordecai Wyatt), 1949 September 30-December 3 (Box 3, Folder 106)
      To: 2 / From: 3
    - Johnson Publishers correspondence with John H. Johnson and others, 1945-1952 (Box 3, Folder 107)
      To: 10 / From: 12
    - Jones, Madison S., 1945 December 26 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - "Ka - Kz" General (Box 3, Folder 109)
      To: 14 / From: 10
    - Kaleta, Stephen correspondence with Antonio N. Sadlak, 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 110)
      To: 11 / From: 7
    - Kaplan, Kivie, 1954 December 16-1955 March 18 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1929-1934 (Box 3, Folder 112)
      To: 10 / From: 0
    - "La - Lh" General (Box 3, Folder 113)
      To: 24 / From: 15
    - Lampkin, Daisy E. (Daisy Elizabeth), 1950 January 26-March 20 (Box 3, Folder 114)
      To: 1 / From: 3
    - Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1947-1955 (Box 3, Folder 115)
      To: 7 / From: 4
    - W. Colston Leigh, Inc., 1943 March 6-1948 November 23 (Box 4, Folder 116)
      To: 27 / From: 14
    - W. Colston Leigh, Inc., 1948 October 20-1949 April 28 (Box 4, Folder 117)
      To: 36 / From: 18
    - W. Colston Leigh, Inc., 1949 May 12-1950 April 14, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 118)
      To: 30 / From: 13
    - W. Colston Leigh, Inc., 1948, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Lewis, Sinclair, 1947 August 18 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - "Li - Lz" General (Box 4, Folder 121)
      To: 25 / From: 6
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1938 April 23 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Logan, Rayford, 1949 March 30-November 16 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Looby, Z. Alexander (Zephaniah Alexander), 1950 February 9- May 2 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Look Magazine, 1944-1952, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 125)
      To: 12 / From: 14
    - Look Magazine draft of "Has Science Conquered the Color Line" and letters re: article, [circa 1949] (Box 4, Folder 126)
      To: 16 / From: 1
    - "Ma - Mh" General (Box 4, Folder 127)
      To: 34 / From: 18
    - Magloire, Paul Eugène, 1950-1955, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 128)
      To: 4 / From: 8
    - MacCarthy, Desmond
    - Manley, Norman Washington, 1950-1955 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Marshall, Thurgood, 1938-1954 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Martin, Helen and Eugene, 1929-1955 (Box 4, Folder 131)
      To: 15 / From: 4
    - Martin, Louis E.
      See: Chicago Defender, Box 1, folder 38
    - McBride, Mary Margaret, 1948 March 3-1950 October 17, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 132)
      To: 4 / From: 1
    - McCormick, Fowler, 1949 September 16-1950 March 28 (Box 4, Folder 133)
      To: 6 / From: 10
    - McCray, John H. (John Henry), 1950 January 24-February 17 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - McKay, Claude, 1931 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - McLeod, Thomas G. (Thomas Gordon), 1926 October 28 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1920 June 11-1929 June 7, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Methodist Student Movement, 1949 December 16-1950 February 13, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 138)
      To: 10 / From: 2
    - "Mi - Mz" General (Box 4, Folder 139)
      To: 23 / From: 8
    - Mitchell, Clarence M. (Clarence Maurice), 1949-1955 (Box 4, Folder 140)
      To: 9 / From: 3
    - Moon, Henry Lee, 1950-1955 (Box 5, Folder 141)
      To: 7 / From: 1
    - Morin, Luis Muñoz, 1950-1955, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 142)
      To: 2 / From: 5
    - Murphy, Carl
      See: Afro-American, Box 1, folder 3
    - Muse, Clarence, 1938 April 22 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - "Na - Newc" General (Box 5, Folder 144)
      To: 27 / From: 4
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1929-1955, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 145)
      To: 23 / From: 7
    - Nearing, Scott, 1930 December 9 (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1949-1954, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - "Newm - Nz" General (Box 5, Folder 148)
      To: 12 / From: 6
    - New York (State), 1948-1952 (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - Novik, Morris S., 1952 May l9-August 26, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - Nunn, William Goldwin
      See: Pittsburgh Courier, Box 5, folder 165
    - "Oa - Oz" General (Box 5, Folder 151)
      To: 14 / From: 9
    - O'Neill, Eugene, 1924 October 12 (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Oram, Harold L.
      See: Graphic Syndicate, Box 2, folder 73
    - Orchard, Thomas, 1950 January 3-March 3 (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - "Pa - Pz" General (Box 5, Folder 154)
      To: 26 / From: 11
    - Pan-African Congress, 1921 July 25-September 28 (Box 5, Folder 155)
      To: 20 / From: 2
    - Pan American World Airways correspondence with Richard N. Barkle and John Creedy, 1949 October 3-1950 May 5 (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - Pandit, Vijaya Lakshmi, 1947-1955, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 157)
      To: 14 / From: 29
    - Pandit, Vijaya Lakshmi, 1947 September 19-November 17 (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - Pearson, Drew, 1935 September 9 (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Perry, Leslie Sterling, 1950, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - Philippe, Charles Claudius, 1952 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 161)
    - Philippe, Claudia, 1952 June 6, 1954 August 26, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - Pickens, William, 1931 May 22 (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Pierce, Billy, 1930 September 18 (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Pittsburgh Courier, 1949 December 15-1950 March 23 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Poston, Theodore R., 1949 September 27, 1950 February 1 (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., 1949 November 15 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - "Ra - Rz" General (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Randolph, Asa Philip, 1929 October 3 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Randolph, Richetta G., 1928-1954, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 170)
      To: 7 / From: 0
    - Readers Digest, 1944-1953 (Box 6, Folder 171)
      To: 35 / From: 12
    - Readers Letters A-J (Box 6, Folder 172)
      To: 11 / From: 2
    - Readers Letters K-Z and anonymous (Box 6, Folder 173)
      To: 20 / From: 3
    - Reid, Helen Rogers, 1949-1952 (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - Reuther, Victor and Walter, 1949 December 22-1950 March 20 (Box 6, Folder 175)
      To: 2 / From: 8
    - Reuther, Walter P., 1949 November 22-December 27 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Robinson, Bill ("Bojangles"), 1949 October 20, 1950 February 7 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1950 May 5 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1944-1954 (Box 6, Folder 179)
      Includes copies of letters from Hurbert T. Delany to Frederick Woltman dated 1950 February 15 and from Roy Wilkins to Roosevelt dated 1949 December 5.
      To: 17 / From: 15
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1938-1945, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - Franklin D. Roosevelt Foundation, 1949 July 14-1950 March 28 (Box 6, Folder 181)
      To: 8 / From: 5
    - Roper, Elmo, 1949-1955 (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - Rosenblum, Harry, 1950 January 17-1951 September 10 (Box 6, Folder 183)
    - Ryan, James Joseph, 1949 October 26-1950 March 17, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 184)
    - "Sa - Sl" General (Box 6, Folder 185)
      To: 25 / From: 17
    - Sampson, Edith, 1949 September 26-1950 March 28 (Box 6, Folder 186)
    - Schary, Dore, 1949 October 20-1950 April 13 (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - Schuyler, George Samuel, 1929 October 4, 1932 June 22 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - Scott, Charles Prestwich
    - Segregation in Public Schools, 1953 May 1, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - Selznick, David O., 1946 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 190)